Okay, so this lesson is about scope
management.
I remember scope management is trying to
determine what is
included, what is excluded.
It's trying to make sure we understand
what we're going to be delivering.
So we're doing all the work
necessary to complete the
project and only the work
necessary to complete the project.
Now there are two types of scope that you
have to be able to distinguish between.
you have something called the product
scope and something called the project
scope right so let's talk about each one
now the product scope let's talk about the
product scope first the product scope
refers to the what it refers to what we
are trying to build what we are trying to
make what we are trying to deliver so it
refers to basically the
features the functions
specific this is what the customer wants.
This is what we are trying to deliver.
And since it's the what, it refers to the
specifications, it refers
to the requirements.
This is what we need to deliver.
This is what the customer wants.
So for example, then, we need to build a
supercar that's going to drive at 200
miles an hour and give us a fuel
efficiency of 200 miles per gallon.
This is what we are trying to deliver.
Those are the specifications, those are
the requirements.
Let's say we have to build a high-tech
home.
Well, what are we building?
We are building this high-tech home.
What are all the features of this
high-tech home?
Well, those are the requirements.
So the product scope specifically refers
to the requirements.
This is what we need to build.
The project scope on the other hand,
this is referring to how.
How are we going to deliver this product?
How are we going to build this product?
What's all the work that is involved?
All right, now we know that this is what
the customer wants.
How are we actually going to go about
delivering this?
What's all the tasks that need to be done?
What's all the configuration work or the
construction work?
What's all the testing work?
You know, what are all
the tasks and activities that
need to be done in order
to deliver this product?
The work that must be done in order to
deliver whatever it is.
And so since it's a how, it's referring to
the project management plan.
So it's great having the requirements,
but now we've got these requirements,
we need to figure out how to deliver those
requirements.
And since it's a how, remember,
how any of the management plans,
the scope management plan, requirements
management plan, cost management plan,
they're all documenting procedures,
they're all documenting the how.
The project management plan is documenting
how we are going to go about executing the
work, planning the work and so on and so
forth, and actually performing the work.
So the product scope
refers to the requirements, the
project scope refers to the
project management plan.
And so it's very important to distinguish
this because now throughout the whole
project management process, right,
when we are talking about the scope of the
project, it's referring to both the
product scope as well as a project scope.
We need to know what we are delivering,
the requirements.
We need to know how we're going to deliver
it.
So we're building a house, how we're going
to deliver all of the
requirements from the.
the customer.
And then plus, not just
requirements from the
customer, but we have
all the coding standards.
You're not just slapping
pieces of wood together and,
you know, slapping bricks
together to build a house.
No, they have to be according to standard.
They have to be according to the building
codes.
So again, all of that then refers to scope
management.
You have the product scope, which is the
requirements and you have the project
scope which is the how the project
management plan now it's often considered
though and it's this mentioned in PIMBOC
as well right it's often considered that
the project scope includes the product
scope so a lot of times we are considered
that we generally in real world
terminology in real world projects that we
will just have a project scope we'll call
it the project scope but it will include
the product scope right so project scope
is sometimes seen as including the product
scope and that's perfectly fine but make
sure you understand the difference being
the two because then when it comes to
quality management as well right we want
to do a quality on the product we want to
do a quality on the project as well